Finding aid for the Clifford Vaughan musical compositions, [1925]-1987 LSC.2265
UCLA Library Special Collections
Clifford Vaughan musical compositions
[1925]-1987
UCLA Library Special Collections
Vaughan, Clifford
LSC.2265
7 linear feet (6 boxes, 4 unprocessed record cartons)
This collection consists of manuscript and reproduction scores of composer Clifford Vaughan, including works written for dance, organ, piano and violin, and other instruments.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Portions of collection unprocessed. Material in the LSC-2003-01 Backlog Material series is unavailable for access. Please see LSC's Access to Unprocessed Collections Policy for more information about levels of discovery and access of special collections materials and registering interest in unprocessed collections.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Margaret Vaughan Meyer, 2003.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9976056453606533
Biography/History
Composer Clifford Vaughan was born September 23, 1893 in Bridgeton, New Jersey, and studied at the Philadelphia Conservatory of Music. Vaughan served as musical director for Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn's Denishawn Dancers during their 1925-1926 Asian tour, composing a number of dance works for the troupe. He moved to Los Angeles in the 1930s and worked as an orchestrator and composer for several major studios, including Paramount, Warner Bros., RKO, MGM, Disney, and Universal. Among his orchestration credits are the films Bride of Frankenstein (1935), Old Yeller (1957), and Darby O'Gill and the Little People (1959). In addition, Vaughan composed symphonies, concertos, chamber music, choral works, and violin and piano pieces. He served as organist for the Mt. Hollywood Congregational Church and wrote numerous works for the organ. Clifford Vaughan died November 23, 1987 in El Monte, California.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of manuscript and reproduction scores of composer Clifford Vaughan. It contains works for written for dance, especially Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn's Denishawn Dancers, organ, piano and violin, and other instruments. Most are original compositions, with a small number of arrangements. The collection does not contain any material written for film or television productions.
Compositions are undated unless otherwise noted. Instrumentation and historical information for individual works was provided by the donor.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the following series:
Series 1. Denishawn and Oriental dance works
Series 2. Organ works
Series 3. Other works.
Related Material
Clifford Vaughan Papers, Huntington Library, San Marino, CA
Clifford Vaughan Music Collection, Peter Jay Sharp Special Collections, Julliard School, New York, NY.
Organ music.; Composers -- Archives.; Vaughan, Clifford, 1893-1987--Archives.
- Denishawn and Oriental dance works, Series 1.
  Scope and Content
  This series contains reproductions of scores written for Ruth St. Denis and Ted Shawn's Denishwan Dancers.
  - Chikada and Bamboo Pole, [1926] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chinese Funeral Tune (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chinese Theater (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Dance for Lana Wang (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - East Indian Finale (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Harusame (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hindu Nautch #3, [1927] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hindu Sari Dance, [1927] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hindu Temple and Bazaar/ Hindu Temple and Nautch (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Indian Peddler (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Japanese, [1926] (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Includes instructions for dancer.
  - Japanese Jottings, [1926] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kapore (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kyono Shiki (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Legend of Pelee (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lotus (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Momiji Gari, [1926] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Pelee, [1925] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Sanjiu Sangendo (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Setting for Three Tagore Poems (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Singhalese Anklet Dance (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Singhalese Mask Dance (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Slave (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Temple Dance and Chant, [1926] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Tibetan (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Two Burmese Dances, [1926] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - White Jade for Orchestra, [1926], 1964, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1, Box 1, Folder 12)
    Biography/History
    Written in China, 1926.
- Works for organ, Series 2.
  Consists primarily of works written for organ; also contains works for organ and other instruments, organ and voice, and works written for organ or piano.
  - 100th Psalm (Box 5, Folder 2)
    And SATB.
  - 150th Psalm (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Aberystwyth (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Agitato (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Allegro (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Allegro and Chorale (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Allelujah, [1986] (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Arietta (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brilliante (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Calmato (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Cantablile (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Capriccio (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Caprice (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Choral Recitative Prelude and Toccata (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chorale (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chorale, Prelude and Toccata (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Chromatic Scherzo (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Concerto for Organ with Orchestra (Box 6, Folder 3-6)
  - Dialogue (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Trumpet and flute with organ or piano.
  - Dithyramb (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dithyramb II (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Dithyramb III (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Divertimento (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fantasia "70" and Scherzo--Toccata (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fantasia and Double Fugue (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fantasia and Fugue (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fantasia Bravura and Fugue (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fantasia, Fugue and Toccata on Hymn (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fantasia, Pasacaglia and Fugue (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fantasy Impromptu (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fantasy on Hymn Tune "Lasst uns Ertroven" (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fantasy on "Land of Rest" (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Flute and Organ (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Gloria Suite (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Commissioned by and dedicated to Mt. Hollywood Congregational Church, Hollywood, California.
  - Grand Fantasia and Fugue (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Homage a J.A.F. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Homage a M. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Introduction and Fugue (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Invitation to Worship II (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Let There Be Light (Anthem) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Little Prelude and Fugue (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Melodie in A (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Miniature No. 8 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Miniature No. 33 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Novelette 1 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pasacaglia (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pasacaglia III (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pasacaglia and Fugue (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pasacaglia with Interludes (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pastorale (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Pedal Study (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Prayer (Box 2, Folder 11)
    SATB, chorus, organ.
  - Prelude and Fugue (Grave) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Prelude and Fugue in A Minor (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Prelude and Fugue on "King's Majesty" (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Prelude in F (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Prelude on "Veni Immanuel" (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Presto e Largo (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Psalm 19 (Anthem) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    [Piano or ogran?], SATB.
  - Quadripartite (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Queen Esther (The Story of Purim) (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Recitative and Scherzo (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Scherzo (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Two different pieces with same title.
  - Scherzo (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Scherzo for Flute and Organ (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Scherzo for Organ (from Symphony No. 4) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - (Short) Prelude, Pasacaglia and Fugue (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Sonata for Organ No. 1 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Sonatina (Classic) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Sonatina II (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Sonatina III (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - St. Michael (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Suite No 3 for Organ (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Suplication (Box 3, Folder 5)
    SATB and organ.
  - Symphonette (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Symphony No. 3 for Organ (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Symphony No. 6 for Organ (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Teach Me Thy Ways (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Ten Commandments (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Theme and Variations (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Thou Art my God (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - To the Glory of God (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Toccata (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Toccata - Adagio - Rondo - Allegro (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Trumpet Solo with Organ (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Untitled (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Untitled, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    Flute, trumpet, trombone, organ.
  - Untitled (Andantina) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Variations on a 16th Century Hymn (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Wait on the Lord (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - When Jesus Wept, [1964] (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Where Were the Children (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Other works, Series 3.
  Consists of concert pieces; ballets; works for piano, violin, and other instruments; SATBs; and arrangements of folk songs.
  - Air and Variations for Violin and Piano (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Air on G String (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Violin, piano.
  - Allegresse (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Violin.
  - Amen (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ballet Symphony (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Blessed Are They (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Chinese Melody (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Color Ballet (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Also known as Color Harmony, commissioned by Doris Humphrey, 1928.
  - Concert Piece, [1939] (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Flute, oboe, bassoon, viola, cello, piano.
  - Elegy, circa 1980s (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Strings and woodwind.
  - Evening Song (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - For Violin and Piano (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - For Violin and Piano (Allegro) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - For Violin and Piano (Slowly) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Frog Went A-Courting, Kentucky Mountain Folk Song (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Clarinet.
  - Incidental Music on Poem by Ruth St. Denis (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Piano.
  - Mexican Hat Dance (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Moods (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - O, Son of Man (Box 4, Folder 6)
    SATB, piano.
  - On Brave Old Army Team (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Piano Solo (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Prelude No. 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Prelude No. 5 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Rise Up (Box 4, Folder 6)
    SATB.
  - Scherzo for Violin and Piano (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Six Piano Preludes (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Small Trio No. 1, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Flute, violin, viola.
  - Small Trio No. 2, [1945] (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Sonata for Violin and Piano (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - String Quartet No. 1, [1937-1940] (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    Full score and parts.
  - String Quartet No. 2, [1940s] (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Symphony No. 3 (Box 4, Folder 8, Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Valse Ballet (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Valse (Rondo) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Fragments (Box 4, Folder 9, Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Notes (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Reproductions of Vaughan's notes on Asian music.